exploros.com 2016-12-10

# Privacy Policy

## **PRIVACY POLICY**

###### Effective date: January 1, 2014

We at Exploros, Inc. (“Exploros,” “we,” “us,” “our”) know that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. By accessing or using the Services—including without limitation the Exploros.com website (the “Exploros Site”) and the Exploros mobile application(s) (collectively, the “Mobile Application”)—you acknowledge that you accept the practices and policies outlined in this Privacy Policy. Remember that your use of Exploros Services is at all times subject to the Terms of Service, which incorporates this Privacy Policy. Any terms we use here without defining them have the definitions given to them in the Terms of Service.

Please read on to learn more about how we collect and use your information; if you have any questions or concerns regarding our privacy practices, please send a detailed message to [support@exploros.com](mailto:support@exploros.com), or write us at Exploros, PO Box 81, Wayland, MA 01778.

### **What does this Privacy Policy cover?**

This Privacy Policy explains how Exploros collects and uses information from its Services users, including our treatment of personally identifiable information. This policy does not apply to websites or practices of companies that Exploros does not own or control, or to individuals that Exploros does not employ or manage, including providers of Publisher Software.

### **How is Children’s Personal Information treated?**

If you are not of legal age to form a binding contract (in many jurisdictions, this age is 18), you may only use the Services and disclose information to us with your parent’s or guardian’s express consent. Review this Privacy Policy with your parent or guardian and make sure you understand it, and do the same with the privacy policies of all websites you visit or mobile applications you use.

We only collect personal information through the Services from a child under 13 where that student’s school, district, and/or teacher has agreed (via the terms described in more detail in the Terms of Service) to obtain parental consent for that child to use the Services and disclose personal information to us, for the use and benefit of the learning environment. If you are a student under 13, please do not send any personal information about yourself to us if your school, district, and/or teacher has not obtained this prior consent from your parent or guardian, and please do not send any personal information other than what we request from you in connection with the Services. If we learn we have collected personal information from a student under 13 without parental consent being obtained by his or her school, district, and/or teacher, or if we learn a student under 13 has provided us personal information beyond what we request from him or her, we will delete that information as quickly as possible. If you believe that a student under 13 may have provided us personal information in violation of this paragraph, please contact us at [support@exploros.com](mailto:support@exploros.com).

When we use the term “Personal Information” in this Privacy Policy, we are referring to personally identifiable information of individual, non-student registrants of the Services. References to “Children’s Personal Information” only apply to personally identifiable information of users who have registered for the Services as minor students (i.e., students under the age of 18). General references to “information” apply to all users.

### **What information does Exploros display or collect?**

#### Information You Provide to Us

We receive and store any information you knowingly enter on the Services, whether via computer, tablet, other wireless device, or that you provide to us in any other way. This information may include, without limitation, Personal Information such as your name, user name, email address, phone number, profile picture, school affiliation and location, billing and payment information (as it relates to Credit and the Exploros Marketplace), and any other information necessary for us to provide our Services. If you are a student registrant, the only Children’s Personal Information we require is your name, user name, password, and email through the functionality of the Services, you may also be permitted to input a profile picture, address, social media information, and a phone number.

#### Required Account Information Collected for a Teacher Account

When you sign up for a Teacher account, you must provide first and last name, email address, and a password. If you make a purchase from the Marketplace, you must provide credit card information and billing address.

#### Required Account Information Collected for a Student Account

In order to sign up for an account, a student must receive a teacher access code from his or her teacher. The access code is automatically assigned by Exploros to each user with a teacher account. The student must enter this code in order to access the sign-up form. The form requires the following Children’s Personal Information: first and last name, email address, and a password. The student account will be connected to the teacher’s All Students list. A single student account may be connected to multiple teacher accounts.

#### Information Collected Automatically

We receive and store certain types of usage information whenever you interact with the Services; this information is not Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information. For example, Exploros automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, Exploros cookie information, and the pages within the Exploros domain you have visited. We also record the details of your activity on the Services, and the number and frequency of visitors to our site and its components. When you download our Mobile Application, we automatically collect information on the type of device, name and version of the operating system, name and version of the application, whether the currently logged in user is a teacher, student, or other user type, as well as actions performed by the user in accessing the Mobile Application (“Mobile Usage Information,” which is considered part of “usage information” as described above). However, we do not request, access or track any geographic-location-based information from your mobile device (i.e., any information regarding where your mobile device is located on the globe at a particular time) at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Applications. For clarity, this does not prevent us from asking you what school you are affiliated with. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that we transfer to your computer or mobile device to enable our systems to recognize your computer or device, and tell us how and when pages in our site are visited and by how many people. Exploros cookies do not collect Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information, and we do not combine the general information collected through cookies with other Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information to tell us who you are or what your user name or email address is. Most browsers have an option for turning off the cookie feature, which will prevent your browser from accepting new cookies, as well as (depending on the sophistication of your browser software) allowing you to decide on acceptance of each new cookie in a variety of ways. We strongly recommend that you leave the cookies activated, however, because you may not be able to log in or use many of the Services’ most attractive features without cookies enabled. Our partners, affiliates, and service providers may also transmit cookies to your computer or device, to help provide you with an optimal online experience. The use of cookies by third parties is not covered by this Privacy Policy and we do not have access to or control over such cookies.

When you use our Mobile Application, we store information related to the use of our Service. We collect all the information you put in our system, including answers to questions, notes, blogs, messages, and any media information, including video, audio, and pictures, posted to our Mobile App, and time you as a user spent using our application.

### **What does Exploros use my information for?**

#### Generally

When you use the Services, you may set up your personal profile, form relationships, send messages, perform searches and queries, and transmit information through various channels, depending on the category of user (“User Category”) you are registered as, and as permitted by the functionality of the Services. The information we gather from users enables us to personalize and improve our services, and allows users to set up a user account and profile through the Services.

#### Personal Information

The Personal Information you provide is used for such purposes as responding to your requests for certain information and services, customizing your experience, and communicating with you about the Services.

#### Children’s Personal Information

We use the Children’s Personal Information for creating your individual account (which will identify you within your Student Groups), customizing your experience, and for sending you notifications via the Services from your teacher, school, district, fellow Limited Access Group members, and from Exploros (regarding your use of the Services) (“Notifications”).

#### Your Email Address

If you provide us your email address, we may send you email communications. Web beacons may also be used in some of our emails to let us know which emails (and which links within those emails) have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of our customer communications. If you are a student, we will only use your email address to send you Notifications and log files. To opt out of receiving emails from us, please contact us at [support@exploros.com](mailto:support@exploros.com). Please note that if you do not want to receive legal notices from us via email, such as this Privacy Policy, those legal notices will still govern your use of the Services, and you are responsible for visiting this Privacy Policy from time to time to review any changes.

#### Your Friend’s Email Address

If you are a teacher and you provide us with another teacher’s name and email address, we will automatically send that teacher an email inviting him or her to visit the Services. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this email (and, if applicable, subsequent “reminder” emails) and tracking the success of our referral program. The referred teacher may contact us at [support@exploros.com](mailto:support@exploros.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

#### Usage Information

Exploros uses this type of aggregate data to enable us to figure out how often users use parts of the Services, so that we can make the Services appealing and relevant to as many users as possible, and customize and improve those Services. As part of our use of information, we may provide aggregate information to our partners (in a non-personally-identifiable format) about how our users use our Service. We share this type of statistical data so that our partners also understand how often people use our partners’ services and the Services to help provide you with an optimal online experience. We may link usage information to Personal Information and Children’s Personal Information that we collect through the Services, but we will only use this linked information internally (for example, to customize your experience), and will not disclose it in linked format to third parties. Additionally, certain usage-related information may be viewable in your user profile that may be displayed to other users, depending on your User Category.

#### Mobile Usage Information

This information is used to determine the device capabilities and usage trends, which allows us to better understand which devices we should support and what features are most frequently used.

### **Will Exploros share any of the Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information it receives?**

Personal Information and Children’s Personal Information about our users is an integral part of our business. We neither rent nor sell your Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information; we may share your Personal Information and Children’s Personal Information in personally identifiable form only as described below. Again, please note that references to “Personal Information” only apply to personal information of individuals who are not students.

#### **Businesses We Do Not Control**

In certain situations, businesses or third-party websites we’re affiliated with may offer or sell items or provide services to you through the Services (either alone or jointly with us), including Publisher Software. We may, for example, work jointly with other businesses to offer or sell products or provide services, or we may work with third-party websites to enhance your online experience. These transactions or services may or may not be commercial in nature. You can recognize when such a business is associated with such a transaction or service. We will share your Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information with that business only to the extent that it is related to such transaction or service; for example, we may share your school affiliation and location with a Publisher of Publisher Software that you have redeemed Credit for, to allow such Publisher to determine its tax liability in connection with such transaction. Such services may include the ability for you to automatically transmit information you input on the Services to your profile or account on a third-party website, or to automatically transmit information you input on a third-party website to your Services profile. We have no control over the policies and practices of third-party websites (or providers of Publisher Software) as to privacy or anything else, so please review all third-party websites’ policies before disclosing any Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information or other content on the Services or on any third-party website (via the automatic transmissions discussed above or otherwise). Exploros does prohibit Publishers from collecting or using any information beyond what Exploros itself collects and uses pursuant to its Privacy Policy, but this does not mean we are responsible for reviewing or verifying the accuracy of any Publisher’s data collection or use policies.

#### **Agents**

We employ other companies and people to perform tasks on our behalf and need to share your information with them to provide products or services to you. Examples include sending email, analyzing data, processing payment, and providing user services. Unless we tell you differently, Exploros’s agents do not have any right to use Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information we share with them beyond what is necessary to assist us.

#### **User Profiles**

If your User Category allows it, you may choose to populate your user profile on the Services with Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information, including, without limitation, your name, photograph, and school affiliation. This user profile information will be displayed to other users to facilitate user interaction within the Services or facilitate interaction with Exploros. If you are a student, the only users who may view your profile are those who belong to your Student Group(s). However, please keep in mind that information (whether Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information or not) or content that you voluntarily disclose online (in “communities,” your Student Groups, to your connections, in comments to our blog, etc.) becomes available to other users and can be collected and used by others, in accordance with the privacy settings you select in your account preferences, or in accordance with the User Category to which you belong. Any images, captions, or other content that you submit to the Services in a manner any other user can view may be redistributed through the Internet and other media channels. For example, if you are a student, the content you contribute in your Student Group(s) will be displayed to other members of that Student Group; however, we cannot control what members of your Student Group will do with such content after you have disclosed it. Your name may be displayed to other users when you upload images or videos or send messages through the Services and other users can contact you through messages and comments.

#### **Communication About the Services or in Response to User Requests**

As part of the Services, you may receive from Exploros (depending on your User Category) email or other types of communication relating to your use of the Services or your user profile. You acknowledge and agree that by posting information on the Services or otherwise using the Services, Exploros and its agents may send you email, contact you, or engage in other communication that they determine relate to your profile or use of the Services. If you disclose your email address to Exploros, depending on your User Category, we may use it to send updates, a newsletter or other news regarding the Services, or to simply send Notifications. If you are a student, Exploros only uses your email address or phone number to send you Notifications and log or portfolio files.

#### **Business Transfers**

If Exploros, or some of its assets, were acquired or otherwise transferred, or in the unlikely event that Exploros goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information may be transferred to or acquired by a third party.

#### **Protection of Exploros and Others**

We may release Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information when we believe in good faith that release is necessary to comply with the law (such as to comply with a subpoena); enforce or apply our Terms of Service and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of Exploros, our employees, our users, or others. We will try to give you notice if we release information for these reasons, but please understand that we reserve the right not to, as it may not be practical, legal, or safe to do so.

### **Is information about me secure?**

Your Exploros account Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information is protected by a password for your privacy and security. We also use coding practices that take steps to prevent attack on our Services from web browsers and malicious scripts, by processing all actions through several permission verifications checks. You may help protect against unauthorized access to your account and Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer and browser or tablet by signing off after you have finished accessing your account. A user defined as Teacher can reset the password of a student account connected to the teacher’s All Student Group.

When you enter sensitive information (such as a credit card number) in our Credit purchasing process as part of the Exploros Marketplace, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). Exploros endeavors to keep your information private; however, we cannot guarantee security. Unauthorized entry or use, hardware or software failure, and other factors may compromise the security of user information. For additional information about the security measures we use in connection with the Services, please contact us at [support@exploros.com](mailto:support@exploros.com).

The Services contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and/or practices on other sites (but you should read all third-party privacy policies to ensure you understand them). This Privacy Policy only governs information collected by Exploros on the Services.

### **What information can I access?**

We allow you to access the following information about you for the purpose of viewing, and in certain situations, updating or deleting that information. This list may change as the Services change. You may currently access the following information, if your User Category allows you to input any of the following:

  * information in your user profile

  * user preferences

  * content in your account

If you would like to request that Children’s Personal Information regarding your child be updated or deleted, or if you’d like to refuse further contact of your child (or, if you are a teacher, a child that is in your class) by the Services, please contact us at [support@exploros.com](mailto:support@exploros.com). A minor student’s participation in our Services, and the ability of a minor student to access the Services, will not be conditioned on that student providing more Children’s Personal Information than is reasonably necessary for that participation or access. We will respond to a request made pursuant to this section within 30 days of our receipt of such request.

To request removal of your Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information from our public forums, contact us at [support@exploros.com](mailto:support@exploros.com). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

Under California Civil Code Sections 1798.83-1798.84, California residents are entitled to ask us for a notice identifying the categories of personal information that we share with our affiliates and/or third parties for marketing purposes, and providing contact information for such affiliates and/or third parties. If you are a California resident and would like a copy of this notice, please submit a written request to [support@exploros.com](mailto:support@exploros.com).

### **What other choices do I have?**

You can always opt not to disclose information, even though it may be needed to take advantage of certain of our features. You are able to update or delete certain information, as described in the “What information can I access?” section above. You may request deletion of your Exploros account by following the directions here. Please note that some unrevised information may remain in our records after revision of such information or deletion of your account, or in cached and archived pages. Some information may remain viewable elsewhere to the extent that it was copied or stored by other users. We may use any aggregated data derived from or incorporating your Personal Information after you delete your information, but not in a manner that would identify you personally. We will retain your Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information for as long as your account is active or as long as needed to provide you the Services; we also may retain and use your information as we deem it necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and to enforce our agreements.

### **Will Exploros ever change this Privacy Policy?**

We may make changes to this Privacy Policy from time to time for any reason. Use of information we collect is subject to the Privacy Policy in effect at the time such information is collected. If we make changes in the way we use Personal Information or Children’s Personal Information, we will notify you via email or by posting an announcement on the Services with two (2) weeks’ prior notice before the change becomes effective. Users are bound by any changes to the Privacy Policy when he or she uses the Services upon the conclusion of such two (2) week notice period. This notice period only applies to changes to the Privacy Policy; you understand that it may not be possible in certain situations to provide advance notice of other changes to the Terms of Service (for example, where a change to the Terms is necessary to comply with legal requirements).

### **What if I’m in a different country?**

When you use the Services, you are consenting to have your data transferred to and processed in the United States. All Exploros servers are currently in the United States, and we aren’t able to process your information within the borders of any other country. Given this limitation, if your use of the Services or disclosure of certain information to Exploros would violate any law that is applicable to you, your right to use the Services and/or disclose such information is revoked, as it is wherever use of the Services is prohibited by law (as described in the Terms of Service).
